

RESEARCHER, TOYOTA CENTRAL R&D LABS., INC

41-1, Yokomichi, Nagakute, Aichi 480-1192, Japan

About me

Daisuke Inoue is a researcher at Toyota Central R&D Labs,. Inc. He is also a Ph.D. student at the University of Tokyo. He received a B.E. degree of engineering from Osaka University in 2014 and an M.S. degree of informatics from Kyoto University in 2017. His current research interests include control engineering, multi-agent systems, and swarm intelligence.

Experience _____

Toyota Central R&D Labs., Inc.

Aichi, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Present

- Controller design for very large-scale systems
- · Exploring applications of quantum annealing machines for control engineering

Kyoto University Kyoto, Japan

Teaching Assistant July. 2016 - Mar. 2017

• Teaching Assistant of Complex Analysis Class

Siemens Industry Software N.V.

Leuven, Belgium

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP July. 2015 - Mar. 2016

• Motion Controller Design for Airbus A330 based on 1-D & 3-D Co-simulation

Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd.

Nobe, Japan

July. 2014

• Development of Nuclear Power Plant Simulator

Education

The University of Tokyo
Tokyo, Japan

PH.D STUDENT Apr. 2021 - Present

• Research on Numerical methods for PDEs arising in optimal control problems

Kyoto UniversityKyoto, Japan

M.S. IN INFORMATICS Mar. 2017

• Thesis: Stability Analysis of Networked Monotone Systems

Osaka University Osaka, Japan

B.S. IN ENGINEERING Mar. 2014

 $\bullet \ \ \text{Thesis: Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization}$

Selected Publication

JOURNAL (REFEREED)

Partially Centralized Model-Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems

IFAC Journal of Systems and Control

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

A fictitious-play finite-difference method for linearly solvable mean field games

ESAIM: M2AN

2023

D. INOUE, Y. ITO, T. KASHIWABARA, N. SAITO, AND H. YOSHIDA

Traffic Signal Optimization on a Square Lattice with Quantum Annealing

Scientific Reports

D. INOUE, A. OKADA, T, MATSUMORI, K. AIHARA AND H. YOSHIDA

JANUARY 8, 2024 DAISUKE INOUE · RÉSUMÉ 1

Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

IEEE Control Systems Letters

D. Inoue, Y. Ito and H. Yoshida 2020

Model Predictive Control for Finite Input Systems using the D-Wave Quantum Annealer

Scientific Reports

D. INOUE, H. YOSHIDA

CONFERENCE (REFEREED)

Stability Analysis of Logit Dynamics with Committed Minority and Internal/External Conformity Biases

Proc. 22nd IFAC World Congress

T. MIYANO, Y. ITO, D. INOUE, S. KOIDE, AND T. HATANAKA

Yokohama, Japan, 2023

Model Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems

2021 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics

Melbourne, Australia, 2021

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

American Control Conference 2021

New Orleans, USA, 2021

Stochastic Self-Organizing Control for Swarm Robot Systems

ICSI 2019

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, AND H. YOSHIDA

D. INOUE, Y. ITO AND H. YOSHIDA

Chiang Mai, Thailand, 2019

Distributed Range-based Localization for Swarm Robot Systems using Sensor-Fusion Technique

SENSORNETS 2019

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, Y. IKUTA AND H. YOSHIDA

Prague, Czech Republic, 2020

Replay attack detection in control systems with quantized signals

European Control Conference 2015

Linz, Austria, 2015

K. Kashima and D. Inoue

Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization European Control Conference 2014

K. KASHIMA AND D. INOUE

Strasbourg, France, 2014

Awards

2016

2017 **Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades**, Japan Student Services Organization

Best presentation award on The 59th Japan Automatic Control Conference, The Society of Instrument

and Control Engineer

 ${\bf Research\ Encouragement\ Award\ on\ The\ 58nd\ Annual\ Conference\ of\ the\ Institute\ of\ Systems,\ Control\ 2015}$

and Information Engineers, The Institute of Systems, Control and Information Engineers

Research Encouragement Award on The 1st Multi-symposium on Control Systems, The Society of

Instrument and Control Engineers

Grants

2014

Vulcanus in Europe (15,540 dollars), Selected students get to go to Europe to study the local language, and
 to have a working experience by EU-Japan Centre for Industrial Cooperation in Institute for International
 Studies and Training.